# **Antoine Soetewey**

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

## Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my research, I am lecturer in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level, at UCLouvain and UNamur. I also give trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service (SMCS).

### Education

2024	PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2016	MSc in econometrics – Maastricht University, Netherlands
2015	MSc in economics – KU Leuven, Belgium
2013	BSc in economics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2017 – 2024	Research experience  Doctoral researcher in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium  - Thesis: Waiting period from diagnosis for mortgage insurance issued to cancer survivors (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand & Prof. Michel Denuit)  - See all publications, posters and talks at antoinesoetewey.com/research
2024 – Present	Teaching experience  Lecturer in statistics – UCLouvain & UNamur, Belgium  - See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching
2017 - 2024	Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
2018 - 2024	Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

## Industry experience

#### 2018 – 2024 **Consultant** in statistics and data analysis – SMCS, Belgium

- Statistical consulting for researchers and academics

#### 2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

## Technical skills & languages

#### Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development

#### Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)